Lesson 54.
第54课。
Instinct or cleverness?
本能还是聪明？
insect: n.   昆虫
We have been brought up to fear insects.
我们已经成长为恐惧昆虫。
We regard them as unnecessary creatures that do more harm than good.
我们认为它们是不必要的生物，弊大于利。
wage: v.   进行（斗争）
We continually wage war on them.
我们不断地对他们发动战争。
contaminate: v.   弄脏
For they contaminate our food.
因为他们污染了我们的食物。
Carried diseases.
携带疾病。
Or devour our crops.
或吞噬我们的农作物。
provocation: n.   惹怒
They sting or bite without provocation.
他们刺痛或咬人而无需挑衅。
They fly uninvited into our rooms on summer nights.
他们在夏日的夜晚不请自来飞入我们的房间。
Or beat agest our lighted windows.
或击败Agest我们的窗户。
insect: n.   昆虫, spider: n.   蜘蛛, wasp: n.   黄蜂
We live in dread not only of unpleasant insects like spiders or wasps.
我们不仅生活在蜘蛛或黄蜂等不愉快的昆虫中。
moth: n.   飞蛾
But of quite harmless one like moths.
但是像飞蛾一样无害的人。
Reading about them increases our understanding without dispelling our fears.
阅读它们会增加我们的理解，而不会消除我们的恐惧。
Knowing that the industrious ant lives in a highly organized society does nothing to prevent
知道勤奋的蚂蚁生活在一个高度组织的社会中
us.
我们。
revulsion: n.   厌恶, horde: n.   群
From being filled with revulsion when we find hordes of them crawling over a carefully
当我们发现成群的成群爬在一个小心的地方时，充满了反感
prepared.
准备。
Pick-knick lunch.
采摘午餐。
No matter how much we like honey.
无论我们多么喜欢蜂蜜。
uncanny: adj. 神秘的，不可思议的
Or how much we have read about the uncanny sense of direction which bees possess.
或我们读了多少关于蜜蜂拥有的不可思议的方向感。
We have a horror of being stung.
我们有被刺痛的恐怖。
Most of our fears are unreasonable.
我们的大多数恐惧是不合理的。
erase: v.   擦，抹去
But they are impossible to erase.
但是它们是不可能擦除的。
At the same time.
同时。
insect: n.   昆虫
However, insects are strangely fascinating.
但是，昆虫令人着迷。
We enjoy reading about them.
我们喜欢阅读有关它们的信息。
Especially when we find that.
特别是当我们发现这一点时。
Like the praying mantis.
就像祈祷的螳螂。
They lead perfectly horrible lives.
他们过着完全可怕的生活。
We enjoy staring at them.
我们喜欢盯着他们。
In trance does they go about their business.
在Trance中，他们是否从事业务。
Unaware.
不知道。
We hope.
我们希望。
Of our presence.
我们的存在。
spider: n.   蜘蛛
Who has not stood in awe at the sight of a spider-pouncing on a fly.
在苍蝇上散发蜘蛛般的声音时，他并没有敬畏。
beetle: n.   甲虫
Or a column of ants triumphantly bearing home in enormous dead beetle.
或一列蚂蚁在巨大的死甲虫中取得了胜利。
Last summer I spent days in the garden watching thousands of ants crawling up the trunk of
去年夏天，我在花园里度过了几天，看着成千上万的蚂蚁爬行
my prize.
我的奖品。
Each tree.
每棵树。
sheltered: adj. 伤不着的，无危险的
The tree has grown against a warm wall on a sheltered side of the house.
这棵树已经在房屋庇护的一侧的温暖墙上长大。
I am especially proud of it.
我为此感到特别自豪。
Not only because it has survived several severe winters.
不仅因为它在几个严重的冬季中幸存下来。
luscious: adj. 甘美的
But because it occasionally produces luscious peaches.
但是因为它偶尔会产生甜美的桃子。
During the summer.
在夏天。
I noticed that the leaves of the tree were beginning to wither.
我注意到树的叶子开始枯萎。
insect: n.   昆虫, aphid: n.   蚜虫, underside: n.   底面，下侧
Clusters of tin insects called aphids were to be found on the underside of the leaves.
在叶子的底面发现了一群称为蚜虫的锡昆虫。
colony: n.   一群
They were visited by a large colony of ants which obtained a sort of honey from them.
一大批蚂蚁拜访了他们，从中获得了一种蜂蜜。
I immediately embarked on an experiment which, even though it failed to get rid of the
我立即开始了一个实验，即使它未能摆脱
ants, kept me fascinated for 24 hours.
蚂蚁让我着迷24小时。
sticky: adj. 粘的
I bound the base of the tree with sticky tape.
我用粘带绑住树的底部。
aphid: n.   蚜虫
Making it impossible for the ants to reach the aphids.
使蚂蚁无法到达蚜虫。
The tape was so stick that they did not dare to cross it.
胶带是如此坚固，以至于他们不敢越过它。
scurry: v.   小步跑
For a long time, I watched them scurrying around the base of the tree in bewilderment.
很长一段时间以来，我看着他们迷惑地围着树的底部刺痛。
I even went out at midnight with a torch and noted with satisfaction.
我什至在午夜用火炬出去，并满意地注意到。
And surprise.
和惊喜。
sticky: adj. 粘的, swarm: v.   聚集
That the ants were still swarming around the sticky tape without being able to do anything
蚂蚁仍然在粘带周围蜂拥而至，而无需做任何事情
about it.
关于它。
I got up early next morning hoping to find that the ants had given up in despair.
我第二天一早起床，希望发现蚂蚁绝望地放弃了。
Instead, I saw that they had discovered a new root.
相反，我看到他们发现了一个新的根。
They were climbing up the wall of the house and then on to the leaves of the tree.
他们正在爬上房子的墙壁，然后爬到树的叶子上。
ingenuity: n.   机灵
I realized sadly that I had been completely defeated by their ingenuity.
我可悲地意识到自己的独创性被完全击败了。
The ants had been quick to find an answer to my thoroughly unscientific methods.
蚂蚁很快找到了我彻底不科学方法的答案。